♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
- ♪ Fix this ♪
- ♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
[Atoy] You were just together earlier.
Where's Ibyang?
[Janine stammers]
What are you doing here?
You're too young to be wandering around.
I was with Tatoy and Janine.
We were going to watch a movie,
but I got left behind.
[Tonet] Atoy!
- Where are you going?
- Did you follow me?
‪PREVIOUSLY
So, come with me.
[Emerson] There!
[Emerson] At last!
I'll go ahead because Tonet and I
have a lechon date.
- [Emerson] Oh, Atoy-- Ouch.
- [teenager] Hey!
Ouch. Hey!
- [guard] Come on, come on!
- [Red] Uh… We're…
- [Tonet shrieks]
- [groans]
[Atoy] You really made me run after you.
Give me my friend's wallet.
[teenager] Wallet, wallet.
Oh, keep it!
I need the voucher. It's important to him.
- Give me the voucher.
- Take it.
[dramatic stinging]
Give me your wallet first.
[grunts and groans]
- [thumps]
- [weapons swoosh]
[grunts]
[Tonet] Good thing I escaped from there.
[Martina, in English]
That's what you think.
‪[dramatic stinging]
[music fades]
[grunting and groaning]
[thumps, clangs, and swooshes]
- [rock music playing]
- [grunting]
- [swooshing]
- [thumps]
[groans]
Girl, that's enough!
- [thumps]
- [groans]
- [grunts]
- [thumps]
[suave theme music playing]
[motorcycle revving]
[sewing machine whirring]
[scratches]
[snipping]
[sewing machine clacking]
- [gun cocks]
- [gunshots]
[thumps and gunshots]
[clicking]
- [clicking]
- [snipping]
[electronic blipping]
[music fades]
Can you stop?!
Leave me alone!
I already have a quiet life!
- [ominous music playing]
- [gasping]
Our lives were quiet too,
then you suddenly came.
Showing off with your suspicions.
[in English] And now, here you are.
Running, hiding,
because you became a meddler!
So, whose fault is that really?
I just wanted to correct what Atoy knows!
Don't you feel guilty that they're
recognizing the wrong child?!
You're toying with them!
[in English] That's no longer
your problem, Tonet.
[clangs]
- [grunting]
- [tense music playing]
[Mongki whoops]
[Mongki cackles]
[Mongki] At last, I can get back
at you now!
- [Mongki smirks]
- [music fades]
- [swooshing]
- [rock music playing]
[thumps, thuds]
[groans]
Ouch!
- [music swells]
- [grunts]
[whistle blowing]
Hey, stop!
- [music continues]
- [clamoring]
You go there, I go here!
- [Tonet shrieks]
- [tense music playing]
[grunting and groaning]
- [shouts]
- [shrieks]
[Martina, in English] You're so annoying!
[grunting, gasping]
[grunts]
[grunting]
[grunting and groaning]
[Tonet shouts]
[grunts, groaning]
[shouts]
‪[groaning]
[clanging and clattering]
[clangs]
[swishes]
[music fades]
[muffled chattering]
- Oh.
- Looks like it hit-- There!
Because of this voucher, many got hurt.
But at least, you can still get
a discount on your…
lechon date with Tonet.
Thank you. Thank you, bro! Thank you, bro.
Wait, the voucher's here,
but where's my wallet?
Where's my wallet?
There! Thank you, huh?
Wait. Where's the 75,000?
I had 75,000 here.
- Seventy-five?
- [Emerson] Yes!
It's gone! They took it!
- Gone?
- [Atoy] Seventy-five?!
No, well… good thing.
That wasn't really it.
This is what's most important.
This is really what I treasure in here.
- Mm, oh.
- [Atoy] That.
- [Atoy] Mm. That, right? Nice.
- [Emerson mutters]
- [Emerson] Atoy, thank you, huh?
- [Atoy] All right.
- [Emerson] I'll go ahead.
- [Atoy] Okay, okay. Take care.
Because, you know…
Tonet might be waiting for me.
- [Atoy] Yes, she's waiting for you.
- Tonet's there.
I'll go ahead. Ibyang!
Bye, Bro Emerson!
Say hi to Sis Tonet for me.
Okay, I'll tell her.
- Okay, okay. Wait.
- Okay.
Okay, bro…
Do you have 1,500 there?
- Please lend me 1,500.
- Why?
- Well, I need money for fare and takeout.
- [quirky music playing]
- [Atoy clicks tongue, mutters]
- Come on!
- Please lend me money. I'll pay even--
- I already returned your discount,
now you want me to give money?
Come on. I'll pay you back.
It's just a loan.
I'll pay you in four installments.
- How much?
- [in English] 1,500. 1,500.
- That, that-- Here, two… Make it two.
- Two…
- There, that's two. Okay, fine.
- Two… That's two already.
[in English] I love you. I love you, Atoy.
Thank you. Thank you, Atoy.
- [mutters]
- [in English] Bye-bye!
- Psst, hey! Get me take out, okay!
[Emerson] Okay, okay, okay!
[Emerson] I got you. I love you, Atoy!
Okay. Let's go.
[Atoy] Ibyang.
Let's see if we can still catch the movie.
[music concludes]
- [dramatic sting]
- [Tonet gasping]
[Tonet sobs] Sis--
- [dramatic sting]
- [Tonet gasping]
[in English] This is all your fault.
You know too much.
[in English] So, it's just--
[in English] It's… It's better
if you die. I mean…
[in English] I-I wish I could say
I'm sorry, but I'm not!
I don't want to die.
[Martina shushing]
[in English] Just-- Just--
- Help… Help.
- [Martina, in English] Shut up!
[Martina sighs]
Help.
[Martina panting]
[coughing]
[Martina gasping]
- [tense music playing]
- [Tonet whimpering]
‪-[music intensifies]
‪-[gasping]
[Red] Hey!
- Where did you come from?
- [Martina sighs]
I couldn't find Tonet.
Looks like she evaded us.
It's fine.
[in English] She's gone.
Oh--
Dead?
She was still gasping for air earlier,
but I think she's dead.
[in English] Can you… Can you make sure?
Where? Where's the body?
There, at the vacant retail space.
At the corner.
She was hit by falling scaffolding.
[suspicious music playing]
[sighs] All right.
I'll find a way to dispose of the body,
so no one sees it.
Did anyone see you?
I don't think so. [gasps]
[music swells]
[Red] Go to the car.
Go on.
I still need to fix something.
- We'll call each other, okay?
- [in English] Go.
Has the woman arrived yet?
The one waiting for me, my sister?
No one has arrived yet, sir.
[suspicious music playing]
Netchai is taking so long.
I got here late.
I'll sit here first.
Is this the reservation under Emerson?
- Yes, sir. Here.
- Okay, fine.
- I'll just wait.
- Here's the menu.
Okay, thanks.
[in English] Thank you.
Okay, okay…
I have a voucher.
[music swells]
So, where do you want to eat?
[music fades]
Let's go to The Lechon House!
Let's meet up with Sis Tonet!
Lechon House?
Ew. Lechon?
I want burger and fries.
Not lechon. Gross!
No, let's not.
Emerson is on a date with his sister.
[muffled chattering in the distance]
[ominous music playing]
This is Tonet's, right?
[Ibyang] Yes.
[Janine] Sis Tonet?
Uh--
[mutters] Where could…
‪[dramatic sting]
Ibyang, get the bag.
Damn, Atoy. He beat me to it.
‪[dramatic sting]
[music fades]
[suspicious music playing]
Let's get out of here. It looks dangerous.
Come on.
‪[dramatic stinging]
Tatoy…
Something's moving…
- [tense music playing]
- [soft grunt]
Maybe it's a kitten!
It's moving.
Maybe-- Move aside, move aside.
[music swells]
‪[dramatic sting]
Sister Tonet?
Tonet?
[intense music playing]
[music fades]
[suspicious music playing]
[line rings]
[phone ringing]
Martina.
Hon, have you seen Tonet?
Atoy got ahead of me.
I think he already saw the body.
I'm just waiting for him to come out.
[Martina, in English] Oh my God, Red!
[in English] Anyway, I need you
to do something.
This is important so we won't
be implicated in what happened to Tonet.
- What is it?
- [in English] I need a distraction.
[in English] Pull out the fire alarm.
[music fades]
Tonet?
[pensive music playing]
- [Tonet mutters]
- [Atoy] Tonet.
What happened to you?
I have to say-- I have to say--
Tonet, don't talk anymore. I'll get help.
[coughs]
- Sir, your order, sir.
- [in English] Thank you.
What's the matter with you, Netchai?
[alarm blaring]
Ma'am, sir, we need to leave.
The fire alarm is sounding.
Ma'am and sir, we need to evacuate.
- This way.
- [patron] Oh no, I brought something--
- [indistinct]
- [line rings]
Netchai, I can't reach you.
Sir, we need to evacuate.
The fire alarm is sounding.
- But what about my order?
- [waiter] We'll pack it.
All right, all right.
Please pack it quickly.
I'll get the bill, and here's the voucher.
- The voucher.
- Yes, sir.
- I'll get the bill.
All right.
[alarm blaring]
[tense music playing]
- [clatters]
- Ah, unbelievable!
Oh no!
[alarm blaring]
[hiss] What's that?
[clicks tongue]
[alarm blaring]
[ominous music playing]
Ibyang, Janine, get out! Hurry!
[alarm blaring]
[Atoy] Get out now!
[sobs] Tatoy…
I'll stay with Sister Tonet.
Please get help.
[alarm blaring]
[Atoy] Stay with her. Stay with her.
Sir, here's your order, sir.
[alarm blaring]
[in English] Okay, okay.
All right, thanks.
Ah, thank you.
[muttering]
Sister Tonet, don't close your eyes.
Don't close your eyes.
- [sobbing]
- [Tonet gasps]
Sister… don't close your eyes.
You still have lunch with Brother Emerson.
Lechon! [sobbing]
Janine-- Janine…
Janine… Janine… She's not…
She's not… She's not…
She's not…
[music fades]
[Ibyang] Sister Tonet! Sis Tonet!
Sister Tonet, wake up!
Sister Tonet, wake… wake up!
I love you so much, Sister Tonet!
Please, please! Wake up!
[Ibyang wailing]
Wake up!
Please!
Sister Tonet!
I love you so much!
[dramatic music playing]
[muffled chattering]
Where's Netchai?
Where did you--
[woman 1] Why is there a fire alarm?
There doesn't seem to be a fire.
They said someone had
an accident, probably dead.
- Dead?
- Yes.
What-- What happened?
Someone had an accident?
Yes, maybe dead.
[indistinct chattering]
[pensive music playing]
Atoy!
[indistinct chattering]
[ambulance siren wailing]
Atoy!
I'll take you home first
before I go to the hospital.
I'll have your mom pick you up.
[in English] Okay, Daddy.
No one wanted this to happen.
Pray for your Aunt Tonet, okay?
Come on.
- [Atoy] Let's go, let's go.
- [Emerson] Atoy?
Oh? You took so long to come out.
Is it true there's a fire?
Fire?
It's um… It's Tonet. [clicks tongue]
She didn't show up at the restaurant.
Did you see her?
I can't contact her.
Maybe she went home.
Who was put in the ambulance?
And why were you there?
Bro…
Bro, Tonet had an accident.
[tense music playing]
She's the one we put in the ambulance.
[dramatic sting]
We just saw her with the kids.
She was impaled--
[gasps]
Sorry, bro.
[dramatic sting]
[titters]
[melancholic music playing]
- [Atoy] Sorry, bro.
- [scoffs]
- [Atoy] Bro.
[ambulance siren wailing]
[Emerson] Netchai!
[music fades]
[suspicious music playing]
They already took Tonet's body,
but I have no update on her status.
[in English] Well, I hope
she's really dead.
Because if she's still alive,
then we're dead.
What was the fire alarm for?
[alarm blaring]
‪[dramatic stinging]
[Martina, in English] We kept on
chasing her around the mall!
If somebody sees us,
for sure, we'll be suspects!
[Red] Good thing you thought of that.
[alarm blaring]
[tense music playing]
[music fades]
[ambulance siren wailing]
[Emerson panting] Stop!
Stop!
[panting]
Stop that! My sister is in there!
Stop, stop! Let me in!
Open this! Open this!
My sister is in there!
Sis! Open this! Sis!
Sis! Open this!
[panting]
Netchai?
What-- What happened?
What happened?
Netchai. Netchai.
- [melancholic music playing]
- [panting]
[heavy breathing, gasps]
Netchai, what happened?
[Emerson sniffles, sobs]
Netchai? Netchai! Netchai.
[stammers] Brother is here.
Netchai, Brother is here now.
[smooches]
[Emerson] I'm here.
Hmm, I'm sorry. I didn't--
I didn't get here right away.
Here's the lechon.
Here's our lechon.
You wanted this, right? [sobs]
Netchai. [sobbing]
Don't give up, Netchai. [sobs]
Don't give up, okay?
Brother is here.
[sobbing]
[in Visayan] Didn't I promise you
that I will look after you?
Netchai…
[sobbing]
[Emerson singing]
♪ Little one, little one, sleep now… ♪
[sobs]
♪ Your mother isn't here… ♪
[Emerson in Visayan]
Didn't we make a promise?
[in English] Promise?
[in Visayan] No one will leave.
- [in English] Promise?
- [in English] Promise. Promise.
[gentle music playing]
[humming gentle tune]
[Emerson sobbing] ♪ Your mother ♪
♪ Little one, little one… ♪
[humming and sobbing]
- [dramatic music playing]
- [sobbing]
[sobbing]
[Cita] My God, Atoy!
How did Tonet end up there?
What would she be doing
in a vacant mall space?
I don't know.
The police and the mall manager
will come here to talk to us.
Brother, Sis Tonet's wounds
aren't that bad, right?
She'll be able to overcome this, right?
[Cita] My God.
[doctor clears throat]
- [pensive music playing]
- [door clicks shut]
Doctor. Doctor, what's the news?
Uh, are you the relative of the patient?
Where's her sibling?
[music swells]
Uh--
[music fades]
[in English] Lord…
[sniffles]
I'm sorry if…
it took me a while to…
speak to You sincerely.
It took me a while to reach out to You.
Please don't be upset with me.
[gentle music playing]
But this is an emergency.
Please save…
[sobs]
…my sister.
Have mercy on her.
She's still young, and…
she still has so much she can do in life.
Lord, please…
give this to her.
If…
If You want, take some from me
and give it to her instead.
[Tonet] Brother.
[music fades]
[sentimental music playing]
- Netchai.
- [Tonet chuckles]
Oh? How did you get out of the OR?
Are you okay now?
Don't worry about me.
I'm more worried about you.
You should take care of yourself.
Don't be too hot-headed.
And cut down on all that lechon.
And your foot, have it checked
because you keep stumbling.
[chuckles]
And be kind to the people you meet.
Open your heart to them.
What are you saying?
[gentle music playing]
Don't let yourself be sad for too long,
because that's a waste of time.
The world is waiting for you.
And I just want you to know…
you're my favorite person,
and I'm so proud of you.
[both chuckling]
I love you so much.
Here-- [scoffs]
Oh, c'mon.
What's the matter with you, Netchai?
You're so OA.
You're being so dramatic!
What's wrong with you? Wait. Sit here.
Tell me. What happened?
What really happened? Come, sit here.
Later, later I'll tell you.
But for now, look!
Miss Cita is there. Go to her first.
Yes, I'll just stay here. I'll sit here.
Promise, I'll stay here.
[Tonet] I'll stay here.
Wait a moment, okay. Wait.
[melancholic music playing]
Miss Cita, is there a problem?
Emerson…
Uh, Tonet's operation is finished.
Uh, we spoke with the doctor.
[sobs]
[gentle music playing]
- [sobs]
- [Emerson] Miss Cita.
[sobbing]
[Cita, in English]
I'm sorry, Emerson. [sobs]
Tonet didn't make it.
She lost too much blood.
[sobs] Emerson, she's gone.
[sobbing]
Miss Cita…
- [sobs]
- [titters]
- What are you saying, Miss Cita?
- Emerson…
Miss Cita, come on.
I just spoke with Tonet, right there!
[sobs] Emerson…
Her body has already
been moved to the morgue.
[sobs]
Netchai?
[sobbing]
No, no!
Miss Cita, what you're saying
is impossible.
I just spoke with Tonet.
She even told me to go to you.
She's right here. Netchai! Netchai?
Miss Cita, don't prank me!
I was talking to my sister.
She's right here!
My sister is right here! Netchai!
[Cita] She's gone, Emerson.
- Emerson--
- No.
No, Miss Cita. What are you--
Ah, Miss Cita, don't prank me--
[Cita] Tonet just made you
feel her presence.
No!
- To assure you she's okay--
- Miss Cita, no, no--
[shouting] Miss Cita, she can't be dead!
She can't be dead, Miss Cita!
My sister can't be dead!
I was just hugging her here!
I was hugging my sister here!
Netchai was here just now!
She was here!
- [Cita] She's gone!
- Netchai! Netchai!
- No, Emerson, she's gone!
- Where's my sister--
No! [bawls]
- Emerson, Tonet is gone!
- No!
No! My sister! [bawls]
- My sister!
- [Cita] Emerson…
- Emerson…
- Where's my sister-- No!
She can't be dead!
She can't be dead, Miss Cita!
- She's gone.
- I was just with my sister!
- Emerson. She's gone.
- She was just here now.
[sobbing] She was just here.
[sobbing continues]
She was here--
[sobs] She's gone-- She's gone.
[melancholic music playing]
- She's left us.
- [sobbing and wailing]
Emerson, Tonet is gone.
- She's left us.
- [wailing and sobbing]
Emerson…
- [sobbing and wailing]
- [music fades]
[electronic blipping]
[tense music playing]
According to witnesses,
there was a man
forcing her to go with him,
saying she stole from him.
Who was that man accusing her
- of stealing?
- [inaudible]
- Hey.
- Ah--
Why did you bump into me? Are you blind?
I know you.
[Cita] Red Regalia?
I suspect Tonet's death
wasn't an accident.
So, now you'll be a policeman?
[Mercado] You'll need an ID and a badge.
I can't produce that.
[Red] Maybe you should go
to the wake tomorrow.
Find out what's on their mind.
Find out what's on Atoy's mind.
[Red] He's a tracker. So, he's like a spy.
He probably has another theory
about Tonet's death.
Our condolences.
[in English] My condolences.
["Mr. Tailor" playing]
♪ Oh, Mr. Tailor ♪
♪ Holding the scissors ♪
♪ One cut, and it's settled ♪
♪ Fix it ♪
Subtitle translation by: Rachel C. Arias